<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts | EMICC Group</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
      <atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Posts</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2021 | EMICC Group</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/media/icon_hua8c16de7726cc20d06ca0226f429b24a_231051_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Posts</title>
      <link>/post/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Congratulations to Prof. Zhi Pei&#39;s group for their research work being selected as Featured Article by the journal SERVICE SCIENCE.</title>
      <link>/post/23-12-21-servicescience-featuredarticle-daixu/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/23-12-21-servicescience-featuredarticle-daixu/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;恭喜裴植老师课题组的研究工作被SERVICE SCIENCE期刊评选为Featured Article。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;title&#34;&gt;Title&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dynamic Rebalancing Strategy in Free-Float Bicycle Sharing Systems: Orbit Queues and Two-Sided Matching&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In populous metropolitan areas, the free-floating bicycle-sharing system (FFBSS) acts as an innovative urban mobility as a service, which provides an ease-of-use feature and extra flexibility in contrast to the traditional shared bicycles with docks. In consideration of customer behaviors, such as abandonment and retrial, which occur in FFBSS, a redistribution strategy for shared bicycles among different user-density locations is presented with an aim to diminish the total operational cost while enhancing the overall service level. To formulate the user and multitype shared bicycle–arrival patterns as nonhomogeneous queues, our results provide a tractable analytical paradigm for a time-varying balancing strategy for FFBSS. The bicycle variation at each virtual zone after each redistribution is determined via a nonstationary queueing model, in which the service time, patience time, and research delay are all subject to general distribution. Then, the bicycle-deployment strategy is evaluated with respect to average queueing length and abandonment rate during a normal workday based on a tailored nonhomogeneous probabilistic matching queue. To verify the efficacy and cost-effectiveness of the proposed bicycle-redistribution strategy, multiple simulation runs are conducted with respect to various times of the day. It shows that the resulting optimal rebalancing strategy is batch-based in synchrony with the time heterogeneity in the traffic demand. Furthermore, several managerial insights are provided to shed light on the rule of thumb in practical FFBSS redistribution coordination.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Congratulations to Prof. Zhi Pei, Yunduo Liu, Xu Dai and Yilun Yuan for their paper published in TR-Part C.</title>
      <link>/post/23-09-18-trc-published-yunduo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/23-09-18-trc-published-yunduo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;恭喜裴植老师、刘运铎、戴旭、袁依轮投稿TR-Part C的论文发表。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;title&#34;&gt;Title&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When drone delivery meets human courier: A co-sourcing perspective&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the constantly rising labor cost and deterioration in traffic congestion, the drone-based service emerges as a game changer for the urban last-mile delivery. Meanwhile, the human courier, as a traditional player in the last-mile delivery, appears as a typical form of gig economy, which is always available but with less revenue to harvest. To help the retailer with the fleet sizing decision-making, a co-sourcing mechanism is introduced, which is by nature a time-varying queue with a finite waiting space. And the orders are subject to cancellation when the waiting exceeds the customers’ patience time. Furthermore, three stochastic optimization models are formulated, namely, the pure stability, the pure profit, and the hybrid models, to jointly determine the optimal waiting space threshold and the drone fleet size, which are then approximated with fluid models. Based on the optimal control theory, the optimal decisions are obtained according to the outsourcing probability and time delay. As validated in the simulation, the proposed pure stability model can effectively stabilize the system performance at the control target, while the hybrid model takes into account both the stability and the profit. Finally, the tradeoff between profitability and volatility is analyzed, and the impacts of the parameters on the overall system performance are revealed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Congratulations to Prof. Zhi Pei and Haimin Lu for their paper published in AOR.</title>
      <link>/post/23-07-10-aor-published-haimin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/23-07-10-aor-published-haimin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;恭喜裴植老师、陆海旻投稿AOR的论文发表。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;title&#34;&gt;Title&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A distributionally robust approach for the two-machine permutation flow shop scheduling&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We consider the two-machine permutation flow shop scheduling problem with uncertain job processing time, which is sampled from no specific distribution type. For the ease of discussion, an ambiguity set with a priori mean and support set information is constructed. We then introduce a distributionally robust optimization (DRO) perspective to handle the uncertainty. To the best of our knowledge, this is the first time that a DRO method is applied to this problem setting. Given that the original DRO model is nonlinear and intractable in nature, we first reformulate the inner maximization problem into a linear programming model with a fixed sequence, based on the duality theory and optimality conditions. By including the sequence decision, we further transform it into an equivalent mixed-integer linear programming (MILP) problem via incorporating the valid lower and upper bounds and McCormick inequalities. The obtained MILP could be solved to optimality with the off-the-shelf commercial solvers. In the numerical study, it is demonstrated that the DRO-based model could effectively solve the large scale instances with up to 100 jobs optimally within 30 s. Compared with the SLP, DRO model always triumphs on the worst-case indicator. And as the problem scale increases, the DRO model gradually outperforms the SLP in terms of the Up-90% and Up-75% indicators. Furthermore, the optimal sequence obtained by the deterministic model is less stable than the DRO model, which can enhance the robustness of the manufacturing system against processing uncertainty.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>祝贺！团队陈勇老师获得省级表彰</title>
      <link>/post/23-04-12-chenyong/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/23-04-12-chenyong/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;2023年4月1日上午，浙江省高校课程思政教学活动总结表彰会在浙江大学紫金港校区求是大讲堂举行，全省各高校分管校领导、教务处长、课程思政工作负责人、教师代表和学生代表等参加会议。团队陈勇老师获教师征文二等奖。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;项目名称&#34;&gt;项目名称&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;面向工科专业的《管理学原理》“中国基因”课程思政案例库构建&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;奖项&#34;&gt;奖项&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;教师征文二等奖&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Congratulations to Prof. Zhi Pei and Haimin Lu for their paper published in EJOR.</title>
      <link>/post/22-10-08-ejor-published-lu/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/22-10-08-ejor-published-lu/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;恭喜裴植老师、陆海旻投稿EJOR的论文发表。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;title&#34;&gt;Title&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Single machine scheduling with release dates: A distributionally robust approach&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the present study, a single machine scheduling problem with job release dates is considered, where the job processing time is depicted by an ambiguity set, with the mean, the mean absolute deviation, and the support set information given. To the best of our knowledge, this is the first time that a distributionally robust optimization method is applied to the single machine scheduling with release dates. Based on the risk attitude of the decision maker, two distributionally robust optimization models are proposed, namely, the risk-neutral and risk-averse scheduling. The two models concern with the worst-case performance and the robust conditional value-at-risk with respect to the total flow time, respectively. Since the proposed robust optimization models are intractable in nature, we reformulate them as two separate mixed-integer linear programming models, which can then be solved via off-the-shelf solvers. Interestingly, it is proved that the mean absolute deviation can be ignored in the risk-neutral robust model. Thus a more succinct reformulation is constructed, which can be rapidly solved to optimum. Furthermore, extensive numerical experiments are performed with the stochastic programming model as a benchmark. And it is observed that the risk-averse model outperforms the others on both the average and worst-case metrics in most cases. Meanwhile, the risk-neutral model is more preferable on the average metric when the jobs are sparsely released.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Congratulations to Prof. Zhi Pei and Tao Fang for their paper published in CIE.</title>
      <link>/post/22-10-08-cie-published-fang/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/22-10-08-cie-published-fang/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;恭喜裴植老师、方涛投稿CIE的论文发表。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;title&#34;&gt;Title&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Robust service network design problem under uncertain demand&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This study examines a robust service network design problem, which aims to select transportation services and distribute commodity flow for consolidation carriers. A robust optimization approach with a penalty limit constraint is proposed to formulate the problem. Furthermore, to make a balance between objective value and penalty violation, we introduce the concept of robustness index. A &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sciencedirect.com/topics/mathematics/decomposition-method&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;decomposition method&lt;/a&gt; with valid cuts is proposed to solve the problem. Numerical results show that the efficiency of the proposed algorithm. A real data set released by a logistics company in east China is imported to validate the robust optimization approach, which yields a robust parcel delivery network design with satisfying out-of-sample performances.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>团队邀请清华大学工业工程系李彦夫教授带来线下报告：《复杂工程系统故障预测与健康管理方法及实践》</title>
      <link>/post/22-07-19-lecture-liyanfu/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/22-07-19-lecture-liyanfu/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;7月19日上午10：00，清华大学工业工程系李彦夫教授莅临浙江工业大学机械工程学院，于机械楼D526为广大师生带来主题为《复杂工程系统故障预测与健康管理方法及实践》的精彩报告。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;主题&#34;&gt;主题&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;《复杂工程系统故障预测与健康管理方法及实践》&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;专家介绍&#34;&gt;专家介绍&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;李彦夫，清华大学工业工程系教授，清华大学质量与可靠性研究院院长。长期致力于系统可靠性、故障预测与健康管理方法的研究，取得了一系列原创性学术成果。论文发表在《IEEE Transactions》系列、《ACM Transactions》等高水平期刊，总被引用3200余次，H-index = 32。国家特聘专家（青年），Elsevier 2019-2021年中国高被引学者，IEEE和IISE高级会员。主持国家自然科学基金重点项目、科技部国家重点研发计划课题等多个纵向项目，授权专利5项，与华为等头部企业开展长期合作研究，获得了较为明显的社会经济效益，获得省部级科技进步2等奖1项。担任可靠性旗舰期刊《IEEE Transactions on Reliability》副主编、《IEEE Transactions on Industrial Informatics》、《Reliability Engineering &amp;amp; Systems Safety》客座编辑、中国系统工程学会系统可靠性专委会副主任委员、多个知名国际会议联合主席、中国质量奖评审专家。&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Congratulations to Fangtao and Kebiao Weng for Paper Acceptance</title>
      <link>/post/22-06-16-t-ase-accepted-fang/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/22-06-16-t-ase-accepted-fang/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;恭喜方涛、翁克彪投稿T-ASE的论文被接收。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;title&#34;&gt;Title&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Urban On-demand Delivery via Autonomous Aerial Mobility: Formulation and Exact Algorithm&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The implementation of the autonomous unmanned aerial mobility is a game changer for the on-demand delivery service in the crowded urban setting. In this study, the first of its kind commercial unmanned aerial vehicle (UAV) urban delivery program in China is targeted. Different from the traditional ground pickup and delivery services, the aerial mode considers not only the time window constraints, but also the spatial conflicts incurred during the take-off and landing operations of UAVs. To obtain the optimal flying routes of the focused problem, a mixed integer programming model is formulated. Due to its inherent complexity, the optimal schedule cannot be attained within acceptable time via the off-the-shelf solvers. To help speed up the solving process, a branch-and-cut based exact algorithm is proposed, together with a series of customized valid inequalities. To further accelerate, a greedy insertion heuristic is designed to secure high-quality initial solutions. In the numerical section, it is observed that the algorithm proposed in this paper can help solve the real-life on-demand UAV delivery problem to near optimum (within 5% optimality gap) within reasonable computation time (in 5 minutes).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Congratulations to Yujuan Wang and Peiqi Yang for Paper Acceptance</title>
      <link>/post/22-04-25-ijpr-accepted-wang/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/22-04-25-ijpr-accepted-wang/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;恭喜王玉娟、杨佩琪投稿IJPR的论文被接收。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;title&#34;&gt;Title&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Energy consumption control in the two-machine Bernoulli serial production line with setup and idleness&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In recent years, the topic of sustainable manufacturing system design with energy saving features has received increasing attention. For a typical production line setting, the machines are subject to random breakdown and restart besides blockage and starvation, and they are usually connected via buffer areas with finite capacity. In the present study, the energy consumption of the serial production line with two Bernoulli machines is considered, with an aim to minimize the total energy consumption under a desired production rate. The energy consumption of the two machine system is composed of the energy needed to set up, for keeping machines idle, and for actual manufacturing. In order to minimize the total energy expenditure, a nonlinear fractional polynomial optimization model is constructed, which is first converted to a nonlinear polynomial optimization problem. Then the property of the total energy cost is analyzed via the sum of squares (SOS) method. To speed up the solving process, a new heuristic approach named ECS-algorithm is proposed considering the monotonicity and local optimality of the energy cost function. Finally, by presenting optimal configurations of the production line with different throughputs, buffer capacities, and energy parameters, a simulation based study is performed to validate the SOS and ECS algorithms.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>恭喜裴植老师当选IEEE T-ASE编委</title>
      <link>/post/21-12-08-tase-ae-pei/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/21-12-08-tase-ae-pei/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;恭喜裴植老师当选IEEE Transactions on Automation Science and Engineering编委&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;    团队教师裴植经IEEE机器人与自动化学会 (IEEE Robotics and Automation Society) 评选成为该学会旗舰期刊IEEE Transactions on Automation Science and Engineering的Associate Editor。同期入选的还有包括美国密西根大学、意大利国家研究院、韩国KAIST、西班牙哈恩大学、清华大学、香港中文大学的教授及研究人员。本次当选IEEE汇刊编委（AE）体现学院整体研究工作水平得到了国际学术组织的肯定，也表明学院在年轻教师培养方面成效斐然，青年教师的学术影响力得到显著提升。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;    IEEE 自动化科学与工程汇刊 (T-ASE) 自2004年7月起每季度出版一次，其与兄弟期刊 IEEE 机器人学汇刊 (T-RO) 由电气和电子工程师协会出版，是IEEE 机器人与自动化学会的旗舰刊物。IEEE 自动化科学与工程汇刊 (T-ASE) 发布机器人与自动化科学领域新的抽象概念、算法、理论、模型、系统和案例研究，可应用于各行各业，以显着提高社会的效率、质量、生产力和可靠性。IEEE T-ASE是国际知名期刊，2020年影响因子为5.083，也是CCF-B类重要期刊。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;    裴植老师自2011年起在我院任教至今，研究方向为制造系统建模与分析，智慧城市物流系统设计。研究成果获中国商业联合会科学技术特等奖、吴文俊人工智能科学技术二等奖。主持多项国家与省自然科学基金项目，发表SCI/EI检索论文40余篇，其中ESI高被引论文1篇。现任IEEE可持续生产及自动化技术委员委员(TC Member)，美国数学评论(Mathematical Reviews)评论员，全国机械工程学会生产系统专业委员会委员，中国运筹学会行为运筹与管理分会理事，中国人工智能学会自然计算与数字智能城市专委会委员。目前研究成果已发表于European Journal of Operational Research、Annals of Operations Research、Omega、Service Science、IEEE Transactions on Automation Science and Engineering、Computers &amp;amp; Operations Research以及Information Sciences等国际学术期刊。&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Congratulations to Prof. Wenchao Yi for Swarm and Evolutionary Computation Paper Acceptance</title>
      <link>/post/21-11-19-sec-accepted-yi/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/21-11-19-sec-accepted-yi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Congratulations to Prof. Wenchao Yi for her paper was accepted by Swarm and Evolutionary Computation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;title&#34;&gt;Title&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adaptive differential evolution with ensembling operators for continuous optimization problems&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Differential evolution is one of the most popular evolutionary algorithms for continuous optimization. In this paper, we introduce a new algorithm named the adaptive differential evolution with ensembling populations. In the proposed algorithm, two sets of mutation and crossover operators are utilized to generate offspring to better balance the exploitation and exploration abilities of the algorithm. Besides, an adaptive parameter control strategy is integrated to dynamically adjust the parameter setting of the algorithm so as to further improve the search efficacy. In the experimental studies, it is demonstrated that the proposed algorithm presents competitive performance on benchmark functions as well as on the real-world wireless sensor localization application, in terms of global search ability and search efficiency.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Congratulations to Prof. Zhi Pei for Service Science Paper Acceptance</title>
      <link>/post/21-09-17-ss-accpted-xu/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/21-09-17-ss-accpted-xu/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Congratulations to Prof. Zhi Pei, Xu Dai and Tianzong Yu for their paper was accepted by Service Science.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;title&#34;&gt;Title&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dynamic rebalancing strategy in free-float bicycle sharing systems: Orbit queues and two-sided matching&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In populous metropolitan areas, the free-floating bicycle sharing system (FFBSS) acts as an innovative urban mobility-as-a-service (MaaS), which provides an ease-of-use feature and extra flexibility in contrast to the traditional shared bicycles with docks. In consideration of customer behaviors such as abandonment and retrial which occur in FFBSS, a redistribution strategy for shared bicycles among different user-density locations is presented, with an aim to diminish the total operational cost while enhancing the overall service level. To formulate the user and multi-type shared bicycle arrival patterns as non-homogeneous queues, our results provide a tractable analytical paradigm for time-varying balancing strategy for FFBSS. The bicycle variation at each virtual zone after each redistribution is determined via a non-stationary queueing model, where the service time, patience time and re-search delay are all subject to general distribution. Then the bicycle deployment strategy is evaluated with respect to average queueing length and abandonment rate during a normal workday based on a tailored nonhomogeneous probabilistic matching queue. To verify the efficacy and cost-effectiveness of the proposed bicycle redistribution strategy, multiple simulation runs are conducted with respect to various time of the day. It shows that the resulting optimal rebalancing strategy is batch-based, in synchrony with the time heterogeneity in the traffic demand. Furthermore, several managerial insights are provided to shed light on the rule-of-thumb in practical FFBSS redistribution coordination.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>恭喜张文珠老师，陈勇老师指导的本科生课程设计取得工业工程类专业优秀课程设计良好成绩</title>
      <link>/post/21-08-31-com-supervisor-wenzhu/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/21-08-31-com-supervisor-wenzhu/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;​		本次工业工程类专业优秀课程设计展示活动吸引了70所高校的积极参与，共收到204份课程设计案例。本次课程设计是大学针对课程的综合性实践教学活动，是工业工程人才培养过程中的重要环节，促进了工业工程类专业人才培养经验交流，提高了学生综合运用专业知识系统分析和解决问题的能力。在各高校和专家的大力支持下，历时4个月的展示活动顺利结束，经过专家委员会的评审，现公布&lt;a href=&#34;http://jzw.ie.tsinghua.edu.cn/Show/index/cid/45/id/1584.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;成绩&lt;/a&gt;。&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>恭喜易文超老师，陈勇老师指导的本科生课程设计取得工业工程类专业优秀课程设计优秀成绩</title>
      <link>/post/21-08-31-com-supervisor-wenchao/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/21-08-31-com-supervisor-wenchao/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;​		本次工业工程类专业优秀课程设计展示活动吸引了70所高校的积极参与，共收到204份课程设计案例。本次课程设计是大学针对课程的综合性实践教学活动，是工业工程人才培养过程中的重要环节，促进了工业工程类专业人才培养经验交流，提高了学生综合运用专业知识系统分析和解决问题的能力。在各高校和专家的大力支持下，历时4个月的展示活动顺利结束，经过专家委员会的评审，现公布&lt;a href=&#34;http://jzw.ie.tsinghua.edu.cn/Show/index/cid/45/id/1584.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;成绩&lt;/a&gt;。&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Congratulations to Prof. Zhi Pei and his Ph.D. students Haimin Lu for Paper Acceptance</title>
      <link>/post/21-08-19-ejor-accpted-haimin/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/21-08-19-ejor-accpted-haimin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Congratulations to Prof. Zhi Pei and his Ph.D. students Haimin Lu for their paper was accepted by the European Journal of Operational Research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;title&#34;&gt;Title&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Target-based Distributionally Robust Optimization for Single Machine Scheduling&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the traditional single-machine scheduling problem with uncertain processing time, distributionally robust optimization models are established in situations where the distribution information is not known exactly. One well-studied robust optimization method used in scheduling is the distributionally β-robust optimization technique. The goal of this technique is to maximize the probability that the total flow time of the job sequence does not exceed the predetermined target level T. However, it is possible that the excess value of the total flow time beyond the target T may be incredibly large, and therefore it is necessary to consider the optimized excess value. To address this concern, two new target-based risk measures are introduced. First, target-oriented CVaR, the worst-case conditional value-at-risk (CVaR) is used to minimize the excess value beyond T, which accounts for both the excess probability and the excess value. Second, the essential riskiness index (ERI) is extended to a multi-piecewise linear function for excess value control in single-machine scheduling problems. To obtain a tractable closed-form solutions of the risk measures, the CVaR-based measure is decomposed into an assignment problem and a second-order cone programming problem, and the ERI is converted to its equivalent semi-definite programming and second-order cone counterparts. To efficiently solve the risk measures for single-machine scheduling, a bisection search algorithm and a Benders decomposition algorithm are designed. In the numerical analysis, the excess value and the probability are investigated with respect to two distributions, namely the two-point distribution and the truncated normal distribution. The experiment design also considers different ranges of expectation and variance, tolerance levels, and problem scales. It is discovered that the CVaR and ERI-based methods are always better than the distributionally β-robust scheduling approach in terms of excess value.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Congratulations to Prof. Wenzhu Zhang for Paper Acceptance</title>
      <link>/post/21-04-21-ejor-accpted-wenzhu/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/21-04-21-ejor-accpted-wenzhu/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Congratulations to Prof. Wenzhu Zhang for her paper was accepted by the European Journal of Operational Research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;title&#34;&gt;Title&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Frequency competition among airlines on coordinated airports network&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Frequency competition is critical for a full-service airline in gaining market share, and adopting a proper strategy can improve an airline’s profits. This study proposes a new equilibrium programming model with flow balance to address frequency competition on airports network with time slot constraints. We first show that a pure-strategy Nash equilibrium may not always exist, and thus forming a pure strategy profile in frequency competition among airlines may naturally lead to deviation from current frequency. Therefore, we formulate the problem as a programming model with a mixed-strategy Nash equilibrium. To avoid shocks from dramatic frequency changes across the network, airlines tend to fine-tune frequencies on select segments during each adjustment. We propose a procedure to generate a computationally tractable amount of representative strategies from a finite set of feasible strategies to demonstrate mixed-strategy Nash equilibrium. We conduct an empirical analysis using an example in which industry profitability increased by as much as 7.89%. We then extend the model to formulate frequency competition among metal-neutral alliances. The results show that forming metal-neutral alliances can improve total industry profits by 10.59%. In particular, a sensitivity analysis with real data on the tolerance of flow imbalance demonstrates that deducting the potential costs due to the relaxation of flow balance between congested airports may earn additional total industry profits in a frequency competition.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
